<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on And So It Goes</title>
    <link>https://tiff.ws/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on And So It Goes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tiff.ws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Controlling Images with tags in Hugo</title>
      <link>https://tiff.ws/posts/hugo-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiff.ws/posts/hugo-images/</guid>
      <description>GitHub-like image control with Hugo using tags, supporting theme switching, and size adjustments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic to-visit Queue</title>
      <link>https://tiff.ws/posts/prob-queue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiff.ws/posts/prob-queue/</guid>
      <description>A probabilistic collection leveraging Bloom Filters to store a set of 1 billion visited URLs in 18mb.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Search Engine in Rust</title>
      <link>https://tiff.ws/posts/search-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiff.ws/posts/search-engine/</guid>
      <description>A search engine overview and Rust implementation, supporting free and boolean ranked queries, efficient disk and memory usage, and spelling correction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Log-Structured Merge Tree</title>
      <link>https://tiff.ws/posts/lsm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiff.ws/posts/lsm/</guid>
      <description>An LSM Tree overview and Java implementation, with a Skiplist, SStables, and background compaction from scratch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://tiff.ws/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiff.ws/about/</guid>
      <description>I got a Bachelor’s degree from the University of Trento, and my Master’s degree from the University of Milan. Currently, I work as a Software Engineer at Amazon Berlin.&#xA;During my studies, I gained a lot of interest in algorithms and data structures, as well as distributed systems, databases, and search engines. I explored those topics with my master’s thesis on graph compression, and with side projects on LSM tree and search engine implementations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Library</title>
      <link>https://tiff.ws/library/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tiff.ws/library/</guid>
      <description>Designing Data-Intensive Applications Excellent book about many distributed systems concepts, databases, and big data processing ideas.&#xA;Database Internals Deep dive into database concepts that the first book only touches briefly, like data organization on disk, log-structured databases, and so on. It also covers distributed systems.&#xA;Building Microservices Concepts tied to developing independent services rather than huge monoliths. Touches testing, CI/CD, communication styles and so on.&#xA;Introduction to information retrieval How search engines work, how they are built and maintained.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
